[
  {
    "question": "How would you concatenate (join) the strings 'face' and 'book'?",
    "type": "drag",
    "options": [
      "'face'.join('book')",
      "'face' += 'book'",
      "'face' + 'book'",
      "str.join('face', 'book')"
    ],
    "answer": "'face' + 'book'",
    "difficulty": "easy"
  },
  {
    "question": "How would you print 10 asterix (*) characters?",
    "type": "drag",
    "options": [
      "print 10 *",
      "print '**********'",
      "10.times('*')",
      "10 * '*'",
      "repeat('*', 10)"
    ],
    "answers": [
        "print '**********'",
        "10 * '*'"
    ],
    "difficulty": "easy"
  },
  {
    "question": "The following code doesn't compile. Fix it to print the expected string",
    "type": "debug",
    "question_code": [
      "print 'My height is 5'11.'"
    ],
    "output": "My height is 5'11.",
    "difficulty": "easy"
  },
  {
    "question": "Write a statement that writes 'Hello World' to the console.",
    "type": "statement",
    "output": "Hello World",
    "difficulty": "easy"
  },
  {
    "question": "Write a statement that stores your name in a variable named 'name'.",
    "type": "statement",
    "check": [
      "type(name) is str",
      "len(name) > 1"
    ],
    "difficulty": "easy"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the correct way to comment out the line \"print 'Hello World'\"?",
    "type": "drag",
    "options": [
      "// print 'Hello World'",
      "# print 'Hello World'",
      "/* print 'Hello World' */",
      "' print 'Hello World'"
    ],
    "answer": "# print 'Hello World'",
    "difficulty": "easy"
  },
  {
    "question": "How would you amend this statement to print each word on a separate line?",
    "type": "debug",
    "question_code": [
      "print 'Hello World'"
    ],
    "answer": "print 'Hello\\nWorld'",
    "difficulty": "easy"
  },
  {
    "question": "How would you fix this statement to print the correct string length?",
    "type": "debug",
    "question_code": [
      "print length('Hello World')"
    ],
    "answer": "print len('Hello World')",
    "difficulty": "easy"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many characters are in the output of \"print 'Hello\\nWorld'\"?",
    "type": "drag",
    "options": [
      "05",
      "10",
      "11",
      "12"
    ],
    "answer": "11",
    "difficulty": "easy"
  },
  {
    "question": "What statement would you use to access the first element of 'animals'?",
    "type": "statement",
    "question_code": [
      "animals = ['lion', 'tiger', 'penguin', 'kangaroo']"
    ],
    "answer": "animals[0]",
    "difficulty": "easy"
  },
  {
    "question": "Drag the correct escape sequence to print a new line (linefeed)?",
    "type": "drag",
    "options": [
      "\\a",
      "\\t",
      "\\r",
      "\\v",
      "\\n",
      "\\b"
    ],
    "answer": "\\n",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "hint": "http://docs.python.org/3/reference/lexical_analysis.html#string-and-bytes-literals"
  },
  {
    "question": "How would you fix this code to show the expected result?",
    "type": "drag",
    "question_code": [
      "question = 'How many {0} do you have? '",
      "apples = raw_input(question.format('apples'))",
      "oranges = raw_input(question.format('oranges'))",
      "print 'You have', apples + oranges, 'pieces of fruit.'"
    ],
    "options": [
      "change {0} to {1}",
      "type the full question in each input",
      "use the int() function",
      "save apples + oranges to a new variable to print"
    ],
    "answer": "use the int() function",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "hint": "http://docs.python.org/3/library/stdtypes.html#typesnumeric"
  },
  {
    "question": "How would you open and read the contents of file 'hello.txt' in one line?",
    "type": "statement",
    "answer": "open('hello.txt').read()",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "hint": "http://docs.python.org/3/tutorial/inputoutput.html#reading-and-writing-files"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the shortest way you can return the first 3 elements of an array 'a'?",
    "type": "statement",
    "answer": "a[:3]",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "hint": "http://stackoverflow.com/a/509295"
  },
  {
    "question": "How would you fix this program to write to the file as expected?",
    "type": "debug",
    "question_code": [
      "target = open('out.txt')",
      "target.write('Hello World')",
      "target.close()"
    ],
    "answer_code": [
      "target = open('out.txt', 'w')",
      "target.write('Hello World')",
      "target.close()"
    ],
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "hint": "http://docs.python.org/2/tutorial/inputoutput.html"
  },
  {
    "question": "Write a function named 'multiply' that takes two arguments and returns their product.",
    "type": "develop",
    "check": [
      "multiply(2, 3) == 6"
    ],
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "hint": "http://docs.python.org/2/tutorial/controlflow.html#defining-functions"
  },
  {
    "question": "Drag all invalid Python keywords to the target area.",
    "type": "drag",
    "options": [
      "def",
      "run",
      "else if",
      "for",
      "start",
      "print",
      "and",
      "wait",
      "loop",
      "return"
    ],
    "answers": [
        "run",
        "else if",
        "start",
        "wait",
        "loop"
    ],
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "hint": "http://docs.python.org/2/library/keyword.html"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given a space separate list of words in a string variable named 'words', write a statement that will split this string into a list of individual words.",
    "type": "statement",
    "answer": "words.split(' ')",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "hint": "http://www.tutorialspoint.com/python/string_split.htm"
  },
  {
    "question": "Write a function named 'test_score' that takes a test score and returns 'Distinction' if it is 70 or greater, 'Pass' if it is 50 or greater, or 'Fail' otherwise.",
    "type": "develop",
    "check": [
      "test_score(90) == 'Distinction'",
      "test_score(50) == 'Pass'",
      "test_score(30) == 'Fail'"
    ],
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "hint": "http://docs.python.org/2/tutorial/controlflow.html"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given a list named 'words', what statement would you use to remove the last element and print it to the screen?",
    "type": "statement",
    "answer": "print words.pop()",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "hint": "http://docs.python.org/2/tutorial/datastructures.html"
  },
  {
    "question": "Write a statement to print the sum of the numbers 1 to 1000",
    "type": "statement",
    "output": "500500",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "hint": "http://docs.python.org/release/1.5.1p1/tut/range.html"
  },
  {
    "question": "Write a function named 'sort_words' that takes a string of space separated words and returns a sorted list of the words.",
    "type": "develop",
    "check": [
      "sort_words('one two three') == ['one', 'three', 'two']"
    ],
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "hint": "http://docs.python.org/2/howto/sorting.html"
  },
  {
    "question": "What statement would you use to print the squared values of the integers 1 to 10?",
    "type": "statement",
    "output": "[1, 4, 9, 16, 25, 36, 49, 64, 81, 100]",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "hint": "http://docs.python.org/2/tutorial/datastructures.html#list-comprehensions"
  },
  {
    "question": "How would you fix the statement below to print a list of playing cards with their rank and suit? For example, '2C' represents the 2 of clubs.",
    "type": "debug",
    "question_code": [
      "[rank for rank in '23456789TJQKA']"
    ],
    "answer": "[rank + suit for rank in '23456789TJQKA' for suit in 'CDHS']",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "hint": "http://docs.python.org/2/tutorial/datastructures.html#list-comprehensions"
  },
  {
    "question": "Write a function named 'factorial' that returns the factorial of a number.",
    "type": "develop",
    "possible_answer": [
      "def factorial(n):",
      "  if n == 1:",
      "    return 1",
      "  return n * factorial(n - 1)"
    ],
    "check": [
      "factorial(0) == 1",
      "factorial(1) == 1",
      "factorial(5) == 120"
    ],
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "hint": "http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Factorial"
  },
  {
    "question": "Given a space separated string named 'animals', write a statement to print a comma separated string of the sorted animal names.",
    "type": "statement",
    "answer": "', '.join(sorted(animals.split(' ')))",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "hint": "http://docs.python.org/2/library/stdtypes.html#str.join"
  },
  {
    "question": "Write a function named 'is_palindrome' that determines if a string is a palindrome.",
    "type": "develop",
    "possible_answer": [
      "def is_palindrome(text):",
      "  return text == text[::-1]"
    ],
    "check": [
      "is_palindrome('racecar') == True",
      "is_palindrome('test') == False"
    ],
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "hint": "http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Palindrome"
  },
  {
    "question": "Write a function 'is_leap_year' that takes a year and returns True if it's a leap year or False otherwise.",
    "type": "develop",
    "possible_answer": [
      "def is_leap_year(year):",
      "  return year % 4 == 0 and (year % 100 != 0 or year % 400 == 0)"
    ],
    "check": [
      "is_leap_year(2012) == True",
      "is_leap_year(2013) == False",
      "is_leap_year(2012) == True",
      "is_leap_year(1900) == False"
    ],
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "hint": "http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Leap_year"
  },
  {
    "question": "Fix this function so that it returns 'Invalid integer' when the value part of the argument is not a valid integer.",
    "type": "debug",
    "question_code": [
      "def convert_temperature(temperature):",
      "  scale = temperature[-1]",
      "  value = int(temperature[:-1])",
      "  if scale == 'C':",
      "    return (9.0/5.0) * value + 32",
      "  elif scale == 'F':",
      "    return (5.0/9.0) * (value - 32)"
    ],
    "possible_answer": [
      "def convert_temperature(temperature):",
      "  scale = temperature[-1]",
      "  try:",
      "    value = int(temperature[:-1])",
      "  except:",
      "    return 'Invalid integer'",
      "  if scale == 'C':",
      "    return (9.0/5.0) * value + 32",
      "  elif scale == 'F':",
      "    return (5.0/9.0) * (value - 32)"
    ],
    "check": [
      "convert_temperature('20C') == 68.0",
      "convert_temperature('2aC') == 'Invalid integer'"
    ],
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "hint": "http://docs.python.org/2/tutorial/errors.html"
  },
  {
    "question": "Using the map function, write a statement that prints a list of the squares of 1 to 10.",
    "type": "statement",
    "possible_answer": [
        "print list(map(lambda x: x * x, range(1,11)))"
    ],
    "output": "[1, 4, 9, 16, 25, 36, 49, 64, 81, 100]",
    "difficulty": "hard",
    "hint": "http://docs.python.org/2/library/functions.html#map"
  }
]